1號直升機 有人報警 普雷西迪奧公園發現一具屍體
Chopper one,we have a report of a body in presidio park.
1號直升機 收到 馬上趕去
Chopper one,copy.En route.
加利福尼亞州 舊金山
確認死者 男性 35歲左右 身受重傷 頭部中彈
Confirming dead body male, mid-30s,badly beaten, single gunshot to the head.
哦
Well
我們得通知FBI 又開始了
We need to call the fbi. It's starting again.
你餓嗎? 要不要去吃點東西?
You hungry? You want to grab something?
別裝出一副很關心的樣子
Don't try and act like you care.
我只想知道你餓不餓
I just want to know if you're hungry.
不 我不餓
No,i'm not hungry.
- 我可不是你的敵人 Jane - 當然不是
- I'm not the enemy,jane. - Of course not.
我的朋友才是敵人 對吧? 還有David
My friends are,right? And david.
你才14歲 這麼小不該約會
You're 14.It's too young to go on dates,
尤其是和一個會開車的男生約會
especially with a boy who's already driving.
老媽說你花太多時間工作
Mom thinks you work too much.
這又有什麼關係?
What does that have to do with anything?
你們倆合不來 又不是我的錯
It's not my fault that you two don't get along.
我不是這意思
I'm not saying it is.
你想把我攆走
You're trying to ship me off.
- 你媽和我都愛你 - 別來這套...
- Your mom and i love you. - Don't even.
好吧 你想被當做成年人對待 行啊
Ok. You want to be treated like an adult,fine.
那我們就來場成年人之間的對話
Let's have an adult conversation.
有什麼能幫你嗎?
Can i help you?
今晚那麼多直升機在幹嘛呢?
What do you think's going on with the helicopters tonight?
抱歉 我只想跟我女兒談談
I'm sorry,i'm trying to have a conversation with my daughter.
我沒在問你 我在問Jane
I wasn't talking to you. I was talking to jane.
- 你怎麼知道我女兒的名字? - 這堣ㄛO你說了算
- How do you know my daughter's name? - You're not in charge here.
- Jane 你先跑 - 不行!
- Jane,run ahead. - No!
你們保持安靜 否則都會死
No,you come quiet. Or you both die.
華盛頓特區
- Hotch - Cooper
- Hotch. - Cooper.
你不是坐辦公室的料
You never were one for offices.
身體問題 我對官僚主義過敏
A medical condition. I'm allergic to bureaucracy.
- 謝謝你能來 Hotch - 不客氣
- Thanks for coming,hotch. - Sure.
- 我沒多少時間 我們要趕去辦案 - 我知道 舊金山
- I don't have long. We're leaving on a case. - I know. San francisco.
- 我聽說了 - 到底怎麼回事?
- I hear things. - So what's going on?
你對正在調查的案子瞭解多少?
How much you know about this case you're working?
我正要去看文件
I'm on my way in to look at the files.
- 要我給你做個匯報嗎? - 好的
- Can i give you a preview? - Sure.
好了 事情是這樣的
All right,so, here's the deal.
2年前 普雷西迪奧公園發現一名男性死者
2 years ago,a dead male turned up in presidio park.
遍體鱗傷
A massive amount of blunt force trauma.
包括自衛時留下的傷口 後腦勺中彈
Defensive wounds, single gunshot to the back of the head.
接下來的3天 又有3名遇害者 相同的作案手法 那之後就斷了線
And over the next 3 days, 3 more vics,same m.o., and after that, there was nothing.
一整年後 同樣的案子
Until exactly one year later. Same thing.
男性死者 身體受重傷 被槍斃(頭部中彈)
Dead male,badly beaten, shot execution style,
接下來的3天 又有3人遇害
Followed by 3 more vics over the next 3 days.
- 然後又風平浪靜 直到昨晚 - 剛好一整年
- And then nothing until last night. - One year later. Exactly.
在線索斷掉之前 我們有3天時間
Which means we have 3 days before the trail goes cold again.
為什麼這麼感興趣?
Why all the interest?
我有看法 我認為 有另外謀殺案和這案子有聯繫
I got a theory. I think there are parallel murders linked to these cases.
2年前 在兇殺案停止後1天
2 years ago,one day after those murders stopped,
單身父親和15歲的黑髮女兒陳屍車中
A single dad and his 15-year-old brunette daughter were found dead in their car.
去年...
Last year...
同樣 男性死者停止出現後一天 一樣的案件
Again,one day after the dead males stopped showing up, same thing.
另一個父親和黑髮女兒
Another dad and his brunette daughter.
你認為這些都有聯繫?
And you think it's all connected?
世上沒這麼巧的事 你覺得呢?
I think it's a hell of a coincidence,don't you?
- 你想讓我帶你的人去跟進這案子 - 你只有3天的時間
- And you want me to bring your team in on the case. - You only have 3 days.
你可沒時間追蹤這類交叉案件
I mean,you don't have time to be chasing an angle like this one.
我的人在普雷西迪奧公園調查死者
So my team works the bodies in presidio park
而你的人著手父女遇害案
while your team tests the theory about the fathers and daughters.
如果我是對的 兩個案子能相互幫助
And if i'm right, both halves of the case help solve the other half.
你已經問過主任 但她不答應
And you already asked the director and she said no.
她的腦子還沒開竅
She is not strong at thinking outside the box.
如果你忽視她命令 而且錯了 那你就玩完了
If you ignore her order and you're wrong, you're done.
聽我說 Hotch...
I'm telling you,hotch...
你我說話這會兒 一個父親和他女兒正失蹤了
Right now,there's a father and there's a daughter and they're missing,
而且沒人在找他們
and no one is looking for them.
- 停下 停下 - 如果我能砸斷鏈子...
- Stop it. Stop it. - If i can snap this chain...
你只會弄傷自己
You're just gonna hurt yourself.
- 停下 求你了! 求你停下! 快停下! - 你沒事吧?
- Stop it,please,please! Please stop it!Stop! - You ok?
你離她遠點
You stay away from her.
我說了 離她遠點
I said get away from her.
- 你到底想怎麼? - 很簡單
- What the hell do you want? - It's simple.
你把她交給我 你倆都能活著
You give her to me, you both live.
你去死
Go to hell.
如果這是你的答案...
If that's your answer.
犯罪心理 第五季 第18集
Criminal Minds Season05 Episode18 The Fight
特蕾莎修女曾經說過  "我終於明白了這個悖論"
Mother teresa said, "i have found the paradox.
"如果愛至成傷 你就會發現 傷痛盡失 卻平添愛意"
"that if you love until it hurts, "there can be no more hurt, only more love."
過去幾年的受害者 我們都知道些什麼?
What do we know about the past years' victims?
Tenderloin區是 毒販和流浪漢高度集中的地方
The tenderloin district is a high concentration of drug addicts and homeless people.
所有的受害者都是短期居留者
All the victims have been transients.
所以不明嫌犯選擇的 都是些沒人留意的易下手的目標
So this unsub's choosing easy targets that won't be missed.
他不用擔心獵取目標的難度
He's not concerned with the challenge of the hunt.
每次殺人 都只是他龐大計劃的冰山一角
All these victims are part of a larger plan.
過去幾年來 他一直固定在這幾天作案
Which he executes in the same few days every year.
Reid 作案的日期有什麼特殊意義嗎?
Reid did you find any significance to the dates?
沒有什麼歷史意義 一定只是對不明嫌犯有特殊意義
Nothing historical. It's got to be personal for the unsub.
JJ 你和Reid去舊金山警察局
Jj,you and reid hit the san francisco p.d.
Rossi和Prentiss去拋屍現場
Rossi and prentiss to the dumpsite.
Morgan和我就去找驗屍官
Morgan and i will go to the coroner's office.
接下來三天大家都不用想睡覺了
Nobody should expect to get a lot of sleep in the next 3 days.
- 那Cooper的小隊呢? - 你說他有推斷
- What about cooper's team? - You said he had a theory.
他相信那個殺害了那些流浪漢的人
He believes that whoever is murdering these homeless men
同時還綁架父女 並且在拋屍後 殺害父女
Is also abducting fathers and daughters and killing them once the transients are disposed of.
所以我們就負責流浪漢
So then we'll investigate the dead men,
他們小隊就負責調查是否有失蹤父女的事
And his team can see if there is a missing father and daughter.
為什麼他們小隊不跟我們一起來?
Why isn't his team on the jet now?
因為主任不批准他們加入調查
Because the director wouldn't authorize them joining the investigation.
他們要違反主任的命令?
They're working against the director's orders?
我們要關心的是被綁架的流浪漢
We need to concentrate on the dead men abducted from the tenderloin.
Cooper的小隊能幫忙調查 是否真有失蹤父女
Cooper's team can help determine if there's a missing father and daughter
他們的失蹤是否與我們的案子有關
And whether it's connected to our case.
如果主任發現你也在違抗她命令 你是在自找麻煩
Or you could get in serious hot water if the director thinks you're helping to defy her.
不 Hotch是對的
No,hotch is right.
我認識Sam Cooper不止20年了 我從沒見過他違抗命令
I've known sam cooper for 20 years, and i've never seen him defy an order.
如果他強烈地相信自己的直覺 我們應該盡我們所能幫助他
If he feels this strong about a hunch, we need to help him however we can.
Sam Cooper 特別督察探員 BAU 分隊隊長
Jonathan Simms "先知" 特別督察探員 待定
Mick Rawson 特別督察探員
不想提重東西是吧?
Trying to get out of the heavy lifting,eh?
Gina LaSalle 特別督察探員
我正在用一個500百萬瓦特的發射機 建一個收發兩用的衛星高頻頭
Actually,i'm setting up a two-way ilnb with a 500-megawatt transmitter
和單極性衛星高頻頭 都是用KU波段的
And single-polarity lnb, both operating in the k.u.band.
她在說什麼?
What did she just say to me?
至少我們有個好裝備 你是怎麼找到這地方的?
At least we're blessed with a nice setup. How'd you hook it up?
我朋友的朋友是個惡房東 給了我們一個好價錢
I know a guy who knows a guy who's a slumlord, who gave us a great deal.
所以 我們怎麼能把 美國某主要城市的一件
So,how do we conjure victims of a crime that might not have been committed
可能未發生的兇案的受害人召喚出來?
out of thin air in a major american city?
舊金山有80萬人口 半數都是男性
San francisco has a population of 800,000. Half of those are males.
所以從女性下手
Just start with the females.
只有45%的人口是白人
Only 45% of the population is white.
- 所以那就是...? - 36萬
- So what does that leave? - 360000.
那麼白人女性18萬 查一下學校缺勤率
That's gets us to 180,000. Check school absences.
把範圍縮小到13到18歲的 深色頭髮白人女孩
Narrow that to girls 13 to 18 and narrow it again to brunettes.
查到他們父親的名字  再查查他們當中沒去上班的
Find their fathers' names and check their workplaces, who hasn't shown up.
沒問題 如果你想炫耀一下
Well,ok. If you want to show off about it.
好 出發 開工
All right. Let's ride. Let's get to work.
所有的拋屍現場都這麼荒無人煙嗎?
Have all the dumpsites been this isolated?
普雷西迪奧公園
他總是把屍體扔在遠離主道和光亮的地段
He keeps away from the main paths. Never dumps them in lighted areas.
所以他一定已經事先研究過地形 說明他有組織性
So he had to have studied the terrain beforehand. He's organized.
而且體格強壯到能一個人 拖著屍體走一段很長的路
And physical enough to haul a body a long way on his own.
受害者方面的資料呢?
What can you tell us about the victims?
他們都無家可歸 沒有目擊者
They were all living on the streets. No witnesses.
我們猜想 他用食物或者毒品誘惑他們
Our guess is he managed to lure them, promising food or drugs.
- 有任何人報告他們的失蹤嗎? - 沒有
- Were any reported missing? - No.
但是他們都來自Tenderloin 相同的幾個街區
We do know they all came from the same few blocks in the tenderloin.
這是在普雷西迪奧公園的那具屍體
This is the body they found at presidio park.
就算沒中彈 也很有可能死於內出血
If he hadn't been shot, he probably would have died of internal bleeding.
看來自己也開了幾槍
It looks like he landed a few shots of his own.
他的頭蓋骨上有火藥的殘留物
There's powder residue in his skull.
被射殺的時候他已經被制服了
He had to have been subdued when he was shot.
嫌犯不聲不響地從街上把他綁走 所以沒有目擊者
So he gets abducted off the street quietly enough that there's no witnesses,
之後他拚命反抗 難道只是為了 讓不明嫌犯以處決的方式把他射死?
But then he fights for his life only to let the unsub shoot him execution style?
換句話說就是  他到底對他們做了些什麼?
In other words,what the hell is he doing with them?
打開他手銬
Unlock 'em.
還沒說開始!
Not yet!
起來 我來說說規則
Get up. Let's go.
先把鑰匙丟一邊
Throw the key off to the side.
勝者生存
You win,you live.
輸了 先殺了你女兒 再幹掉你
You lose, i kill your daughter, and i kill you.
明白?
Understand?
你能站起來嗎? 能站起來嗎?
Can you stand? Can you stand?
別偷看 Jane
Don't look,jane.
好的 我們已經聯繫過200多所中學 讓他們提供缺席女孩的名字
Ok,we've talked to over 200 middle schools and run the names of absent girls
- 然後比對他們的年鑒照片確定其人 - 還有什麼?
- against their yearbook photos. - What else?
我們正在排查這份名單中 每位學生父親所在的單位
We're checking bios of the dads now and calling their workplaces.
他沒來上班 你肯定嗎?
So he hasn't been at work. You sure?
兩天了嗎? 謝謝
Both days? Thank you.
有線索嗎?
What have we got?
這是Jane McBride 現年14
This is jane mcbride. She's 14.
昨天和今早都沒去學校
She didn't show up for school yesterday or this morning.
- 她爸爸呢? - Ben
- And dad? - Ben.
他跟公司失去聯繫也兩天了
He hasn't been at his contracting company for the last 2 days.
我愛死這哥們了
I love this guy.
咱們的先知說的對 愛死 大愛
And the prophet speaks. Yes. Yes.
Hotch 我是Cooper 我想我們找到他了
Hotch. Cooper. I think we found him.
McBride太太 我是FBI的Hotchner探員 這位是Cooper探員
Mrs. Mcbride? I'm agent hotchner with the fbi. This is agent cooper.
我們來確認你丈夫和你女兒是否失蹤
We're here to determine whether your husband and your daughter are missing.
- 別... - 太太 你還好嗎?
- Don't. - Ma'am,are you ok?
先進來 求你們 快點
Just get inside,please. Hurry.
- 噢 上帝 - McBride太太
- Oh,god. - Mrs. Mcbride.
你們會害死我家人的
You just got my family murdered.
他是第一個公園受害者
That's the first victim from the park.
那個男人在電話中告誡我 如果我報警 他會殺死Ben和Jane
The man on the phone said he'd kill ben and jane if i brought in the police.
他說如果我需要證明 可以去前門口看看 我照他說的去看 就發現了這個
He said that if i needed proof, i should check my front porch, and when i did, this was there.
他很謹慎
Oh,he's careful.
沒有線索能找出他的身份和所在
Nothing to distinguish him or his location.
他還說什麼了嗎?
Were there any other instructions?
沒 他只說還會來電話
No,he said he'd call with more.
你們認為他會監視我家嗎?
Do you think he's watching?
我的意思 他會殺死我的家人嗎?
I mean,is he going to kill them?
這段視頻是放在三腳架上的攝像機拍的 這意味著他可能沒有搭檔
The video was shot by a camera on a tripod, which means he probably doesn't have a partner.
因此他不可能兩頭兼顧 既要囚監你的家人又來監視你家
It would be almost impossible for him to take your family prisoner and do surveillance simultaneously.
那他之前這麼做過嗎?
And he's done this before?
為何沒人自告奮勇站出來揭發這些事?
So why didn't someone come forward after to say what happened?
知道這事的人都死了
He doesn't leave anybody with knowledge alive.
我們會安排一個探員在這保護你的安全
We'll post an agent here to keep you safe.
你能讓我們單獨談談嗎?
Can you excuse us a moment?
Cooper 聽著 你的推論是對的
Cooper,listen. Your theory's right.
可以肯定他在獵殺無家可歸的男人 以及有家的父女
We know he's killing homeless men as well as fathers and daughters.
但讓我們從這接手吧
But let us work it.
如果你現在回華盛頓 主任不會知道你無視她的命令
If you go back to d.c. Now,the director won't know that you ignored her order.
聽著 我知道你想替我擔這事
Look,i know you're sticking your neck out on this thing for me.
- 我理解 我並不想... - 別擔心我
- I understand.I'm not trying to-- - this isn't about me.
我是想保護你
I want to protect you.
- 還記得他嗎?  - Toby Vahl 當然
- You remember him? - Toby vahl. Of course.
記得嗎 兇手已經招了殺了五個孩子 但你我都有種感覺
You remember we got that confession for those 5 child murders, but we all had that gut feeling.
我們覺得並非他一人所為 這五個受害者類型太不一樣了
We knew he wasn't good for all of them. The preference was too varied.
當地警察結束了調查
Local cops shut the investigation down.
FBI就厚著臉皮發號施令了 叫我們拍拍屁股回總部
The fbi brass,they told us to get our asses back home.
我當然記得
I remember.
這孩子的屍體是另一個兇手拋掉的 聽說這事時 你在哪兒?
Where were you when you heard they caught that second killer dumping this boy's body?
我在丹佛跟進一個新案子 你呢?
I was in denver working a new case. You?
我當時手堥S有案子 可以一直待在那兒
I wasn't on anything yet. I could have still been there.
我不會再無視自己的預感和直覺了
I won't ignore my gut again.
- 我不管這樣值不值得  - 好吧
- I don't care what it costs me. - Ok.
我的人也會一起跟進 我們的人手會增加一倍
My people will be on the record and we'll use yours to double manpower.
我是Hotchner 哪?
Hotchner. Where?
好的 他們發現了另一具屍體
Ok. They found another body.
罪案現場 普雷西迪奧公園
- 一個英國佬怎麼...  - 是個英俊的英國佬
- So how does a brit-- - a handsome brit.
一個英國佬怎麼加入了美國聯邦調查局?
How does a brit end up in the fbi?
很簡單 Cooper和我不期而遇過多次
It's pretty simple. Cooper and i bumped into each other a few times.
10個月前 他們讓他自己挑人組個小組
10 months ago they told him he could hand-pick a new team.
他通知我 我就來了 跟國籍沒關係
He called. I came. Passport didn't matter.
聽說英國特種部隊的人 都不能承認自己的身份
So,is it true that no one in the british special forces is allowed to admit they're in it?
我不知道 我還得打聽打聽呢
I don't know. I'd have to ask around about that one.
- 你知道 關於你上司 流言可不少 - 是麼?
- You know,there's a lot of rumors about your boss. - Yeah?
我聽說 他離開BAU時 正在海外參與心理戰
One i heard was when he left the bau, he was doing psychological ops overseas.
嗯 我對這些八卦從來不感興趣
Well... I've never been big on rumors.
我猜你也不會告訴我 你們在哪偶遇了
So,i don't suppose you're going to tell me just where you two bumped into each other.
我可以告訴你 我全身心信任他
I'll tell you i trust the man with my life.
我可以為他去拚命
I'll tell you i'd die for the man.
- 失蹤者家屬怎麼樣了? - 她在堅持 但我不覺得她能幫上忙
- How's the mom? - She's holding up. I don't know how much help she's going to be.
Tenderloin區到處是癮君子 容易控制
So,the tenderloin is full of junkies who would be easy to control,
但第一個死者體內沒有毒品 這怪傢伙看起來也挺健康
But the first victim had no drugs in his system, and this geezer looks pretty healthy,too.
除了他已經死了這個事實外
Except for the whole dead thing.
他的指甲埵野祧妥搵d
There's skin under his nails.
第一個受害者胸部不是有抓痕麼
Didn't the first victim have scratch marks on his chest?
對 我們猜想死者跟不明嫌犯打鬥過
Yeah. We assumed he fought back against the unsub,
事實上 這些受害者可能是彼此毆鬥
But these victims might actually be fighting each other.
一點沒錯
Exactly.
我猜 你有個可以震驚我的結論了
I take it you're about to wow me with a theory.
第一個死者在父女失蹤前被拋屍 為什麼
The first victim is dumped before the fathers and daughters are taken. Why?
因為他要提醒失蹤者家屬 他是認真的
Because he wants to send a message to the wife that he means business,
保證她不會報警
Make sure she doesn't call the police.
而且還給他綁架了的人一個信息
And it also sends a message to the prisoners he already has.
打不過 就得死 你怎麼看這些傷痕?
You lose a fight,you die. What do those welts look like to you?
我的想法 橡皮子彈打的
My guess--they're wounds from rubber bullets.
- 跟獄警平息監獄騷亂用的子彈一樣 - 沒錯
- Like they use to control rioters or prison inmates. - Ok.
我認為不明嫌犯曾經入獄過
I think the unsub's been locked up.
在那堨L學會了怎麼控制囚犯
That's where he's learned to control his own prisoners.
如果他懂得控制 為啥還要他們打鬥
Well,if he's learned how to dominate them, why are they fighting each other?
這肯定是他計劃的一部分
It has to be part of his plan--
親眼看著他們互相打鬥
To watch them beat the hell out of each other.
然後處決失敗者
And then the loser is executed.
承認吧 覺得我有兩把刷子了吧
Admit it--i'm starting to grow on you.
Hotch 是Emily
Hotch,it's emily.
我們可能知道他對受害者做了什麼
We have an idea about what he might be doing with the victims.
我們可以開始側寫了 等等
We may be able to give the profile-- Hold on a second.
嗨 你在打給誰
Hey,who are you calling?
如果我是對的 還有人需要知道
If i'm right, there's somewhere else we need to be delivering that profile.
聖昆廷監獄
- 這是你書媦g的地方吧 - 沒錯 你在這花了很多時間麼
- This is one for the books,huh? - Yeah. You spend much time here?
可能做過六次面談 你呢
Maybe a half a dozen interviews. You?
待了六年三個月零四天
6 years,3 months, 4 days.
- 我們的先知回來了 - 最近如何 兄弟
- The prophet returns. - What up,man? How you doin'?
這是Nelson G. 我們就是在那時候認識的
This is nelson g. Me and him know each other from back in the dark days.
我從沒想過還能在這再見到你
Man. Never expected to ever see you in here again.
- 這是FBI的David Rossi探員 - FBI?
- This is agent david rossi,fbi. - Fbi?
這麼快你就被FBI抓回來了?
The first time i see you in how long and you bring the fbi?
不是吧
Get the hell outta here.
我說過如果我能贖罪 我會棄暗投明
I told you,man, if i ever got my shot at redemption, i was gonna take my game to the other side.
"開瞎子的眼 領被囚的出牢獄"
"to open the blind eyes, "to take the prisoner out of the prison and them...
"領坐於黑暗的出監牢"(以賽亞書42.7)
And them that sit in darkness out of the prison house."
我猜事實確實是這樣的
Well... It makes sense, i guess.
規則都是罪犯定的 警察只能學著適應
The criminals are the ones who make the rules,right? Cops are the ones who gotta learn.
- 我需要你的幫助 - 說吧
- I need your help,man. - Talk.
我們在抓捕一個連壞殺手
We have a serial killer.
我們認為他在這服過刑
We think he might have done time here.
我們有側寫 如果認識他 告訴我們
We want to give you a description, and then you tell us if you recognize him.
利用下你獄中的關係
Just press your connections.
這個不明嫌犯很可能有犯罪記錄
It's very likely that this unsub has a prison record.
白人 據被綁者的年齡判斷 嫌犯30多歲
He's white,and judging by the age of the people he abducts, most likely in his 30s.
考慮到他棄屍的地點
And considering the terrain in which he's dumping the bodies,
我們認為他很強壯 至少身體很健康
We think that he's imposing or at least very physically fit.
他有足夠的空間來囚禁 控制這些受害者
He also has access to a space that's large enough to house and control a number of prisoners,
不會打擾到鄰居
All without disturbing the neighbors.
這傢伙堅守著相同的綁架和拋屍地點
This guy keeps to the same hunting ground. Same dumpsite.
證明他是個真正有組織的控制狂
He's a control freak. Real organized.
而且 他沉迷於模仿監獄的守衛
Also,he would have been obsessed with the guards,
尤其是在放風時控制犯人的方式
Their methods of controlling the prisoners, especially in the yard.
這個人每年會在同樣的時間殺人
This dude kills folks the same few days every year.
他如此沉迷 他不可能沒有談論過
There's no way he's that obsessed and he's not talking about it.
我們認為他有個像Jane 那樣的深發女兒
We think the man has a daughter of his own, most likely a brunette like jane.
他選的作案日期 很可能跟發生 在他女兒身上的事件一致
The dates he chooses probably correspond to an event involving his own daughter.
我們猜測他女兒可能丟了
Our guess is that he lost his daughter in some way
而且當時不在她身邊
And it's symbolic of him not fighting for her in the first place.
很多時間殺手都會選替代品下手  比如妻子或者母親
A lot of times killers choose victims that are surrogates for someone, like a wife or a mother.
我們認為他選了自己的替代人下手
In this case, we think his own guilt is making him choose surrogates that represent himself.
警部的人都知道側寫了 他們在Tenderloin加倍巡邏
The police department has the profile. They've tripled patrols in the tenderloin.
我想這堣]需要有人來側寫
You know what? I think we need profilers out here,too.
不明嫌犯會來街上 綁架流浪漢 帶回去和父親對毆
He could be out there hunting for homeless men to fight the father.
這小子 他是我見過最好的狙擊手
This kid--best sniper i've ever seen.
他在房屋上射擊靈敏
He could view a lot of ground from the rooftop.
- 你願意在地面呼應他嗎 - 當然
- Are you comfortable on the ground solo? - Of course.
Cooper說得對 我們可以在他 誘拐另一個受害者的時候將他抓獲
Cooper's right. Maybe we can catch him trying to abduct another victim.
Tenderloin區
你什麼裝備?
So,what you wearing?
槍
A gun.
嘿 Mick 告訴我
Hey,mick, explain something to me.
怎麼我在地上 你卻安坐在房頂上呢
How come i'm out on the street and you're sitting on your butt on some roof?
你聽到頭兒說的話了
Well,you heard the man.
還需要我解釋自己的非凡能力嗎
Do you really want me to expound on my own prowess?
那會傷了你自尊心
It's undignified.
聽好 所有受害人都來自方圓4街區以內
Stay on your headset. All his victims are coming from this 4-block radius.
嘿 Jane 親愛的 省點力氣
Hey,jane,honey, just save your strength.
你不能再打了
You can't fight again.
我沒有選擇
I don't have a choice.
就算他們把我每根骨頭都打斷了 我也不在乎
I don't care if they break every bone in my body.
我向你保證 我不會放棄的
I promise you i'm not gonna stop.
我有發現了
Ok,i've got something.
我不太確定 東南角上
I'm not sure if it's anything, but southeast corner.
看到緊跟著那癮君子的男人了嗎?
See the guy clocking the junkie?
說明確點兒行不? 到處有人跟著癮君子啊
You care to expand on that? All i see are guys clocking junkies.
- 灰色襯衫的 - 好 我看到了
- Gray shirt. - Yeah,i got him.
跟緊點 我就來
Stay close. I'm on my way.
他在往南走 FBI! 別動!
He's heading south,ben. Fbi! Stop!
- 別動! - 我什麼都沒做!
- Stop! - I didn't do anything!
你幹嗎跟著那個人?
Why were you following that man?
我知道他有貨 我就是癮頭犯了
I knew he was holding. I just wanted a fix.
我不販毒
I don't distribute.
爸爸!
Dad!
幹嘛這麼堅持呢  她跟我一起更好 我們都知道
Why keep this up? She's better off with me. We both know it.
很快 她就會知道這些
Soon,this will be all she knows.
你讓她每天自己走路去學校
You let her walk home from school every day on her own.
她跟我在一起會很安全 Ben
She'll be safe with me,ben.
她甚至不會想你
She won't even miss you.
你不會把我打倒的!
You won't break me!
那就把他打死
Then it's to the death.
你不打死他 我就殺了Jane
To the death, or i kill jane.
要麼他死 要麼Jane死
To the death, or jane dies.
最後一次機會
Last chance.
我很抱歉 抱歉
I'm so sorry. Sorry.
對不起
I'm sorry.
分析員把數據給我們了嗎
Did your analyst get us the data?
恩 我可以給你一份
Yeah,i can lay it out for you.
很好 把它和我們的嫌疑犯庫交叉比對
Good. Let's cross-reference it against our potential suspect pool.
嗯 我們能過去
Hello. Yeah,we can be there.
要一起去聖昆汀監獄嗎?
You up for a ride to san quentin?
跟以前一樣了 整天去監獄堮M話
It's like the old days, spending all your time interviewing prisoners.
哎呀不要讓我懷舊了
Don't go getting sentimental on me.
有消息嗎?
What we got?
根據側寫 他在監獄待過
The profile says he's spent time in prison.
他很可能丟了女兒
He probably lost a teenage daughter in a way
孩子失蹤日期 與他綁架殺害受害者的日期有關聯
that corresponds to the dates he abducts and kills his victims.
我們把有疑問的日期分成了4個子集
We have the dates in question divided into 4 specific subsets.
這組是13到16歲的少女 沒有父親監護的
This group is teenage girls age 13 to 16 who were removed from their fathers' care.
這些是同年紀死去的
These are deaths of teenagers the same age.
剩下的是因暴力犯罪被捕的男性
The remainder are men arrested for violet crimes
還有同獄的
and anyone serving a prison sentence during the same window.
這其中肯定有他犯案的導火索
The stressor's in here somewhere.
咱們得找出點靠譜的線索 好據此開始背景調查
Let's find something that looks promising so we can start running background checks.
- Hotchner探員 我是Erin Strauss - 是 長官
- Agent hotchner, erin strauss. - Yes,ma'am.
我打電話來查問下案件的進展
I'm calling to check on the status of your case.
我們正在查一條次要線索
We're pursuing a secondary line of investigation.
- 為什麼會這樣? - 讓我和她說兩句
- And why is that? - Let me talk to her for a second.
請等一下
Hold a moment,please.
長官?
Ma'am?
你覺得我是傻子嗎? Cooper探員
Do you think i'm stupid, agent cooper?
不 長官 我不認為你笨
No,ma'am,uh,i do not think you're stupid.
我給你的指示清楚嗎?
Is it unclear when i give an order?
你應該知道Hotchner探員與這一切無關
You should know that agent hotchner, he had nothing to do with this.
我們需要得到當地的邀請才能介入案件 而你沒有
We need to be invited in by the locals. You weren't.
但你知道我的想法是對的?
You do realize that my theory was right?
- 我要你今天回來 - 我做不到
- I want you back here today. - I can't do that.
- 什麼? - 明天你可以炒我魷魚
- Excuse me? - You can fire me tomorrow.
現在我只有不到24小時來拯救 正在城市某處面臨死亡的父親和女兒
Right now,i got less than 24 hours before a father and a daughter turn up dead somewhere in the city,
這個混蛋拋屍的時候 我怎麼能幹坐在飛機上
And i refuse to be on an airplane while the son of a bitch dumps their bodies.
我對您尊敬萬分 但...
Now,with all-- all possible respect...
我必須走了 我還有活要干
I gotta go. I have work to do.
告訴Hotchner探員 你們回來後 我會一併處理你們倆
Tell agent hotchner i will deal with the both of you when you get back.
我們說到哪兒了?
So where were we?
我需要你進入這女孩的世界 她是關鍵
I want you to get inside the girl's head. She's the key.
任何觀察都可能有所突破
Any insight could break this thing.
我們需要明白他為什麼要在此時抓走她
We need to understand why he took this girl, at this time.
我到處打聽了你一下
I asked around about you.
查爾斯·曼森被轉獄之前 你真的會過他?
Is it true you interviewed charles manson before they transferred him out of here?
連續三天 1988年
3 straight days,1988.
- 他看起來啥樣? - 小個子
- What was he like? - Small.
- 小個子啊? - 你有什麼料?
- Small,huh? - Hey,you got something?
- 我聽到一個故事 - 什麼樣的故事?
- I heard a story. - What kind of story?
我二進宮之前 這兒有個白人大個子
There's this big white dude that was in before i got sent back.
他看上去就是個瘋子
Supposedly he's all kinds of crazy.
發現他的女兒死後 他就變成了刺頭
Finds out his daughter died, he goes all commando.
打架 練膀子 放風的時候見誰都挑事兒
Boxing,working out, challenging everyone in the yard,
揚言要和他們干到死
saying that he'd fight them to the death.
- 聽起來像是你們要找到的人 - 是 繼續說
- Sounds like it could be your guy. - Yeah. Keep talking.
後來事態越來越嚴重 把看守也給惹毛了
The story is, it got so bad that he started a beef with the officers here
最終他被關到單獨監禁區 服完他剩下的刑期
And they finally put him in solitary confinement to serve out the rest of his term.
你知道是誰嗎?
You got a name?
你在幹嗎?
What are you doing?
強迫癥 我爸爸是個軍人 我們在家都踱來踱去的
Force of habit. My dad was army. In my house we marched.
他一定為你感到驕傲
He must be proud of you.
他只知道 我為了有朝一日能進FBI 而放棄了西點軍校
All he knew is i gave up west point for a long shot of someday getting into the fbi.
很明顯Cooper對你充滿信心
Well,cooper obviously has a lot of faith in you.
他把你從學院奡ㄘ犍X來 對嗎?
He plucked you out of the academy,right?
- 這是什麼? - 這個拼貼畫
- What is it? - This collage.
Jane想告訴她父母 他們不存在於她的生活
Jane is telling her parents that they don't exist in her life.
她的興趣和父母的截然不同
That her interests are an entirely different culture than her parents'.
為什麼她要把日記放在外面 讓所有人都可以看到?
Why would she keep a journal out for anyone to read?
- 堶掉g些什麼? - 非常典型的14歲孩子的事
- What's in it? - It's typical 14-year-old stuff.
發洩說她的父母對她不公平 聊聊一個叫David的男孩
Rants about her parents being unfair, talk about some boy named david.
她反抗了 希望她父母能看到這些
Ok,so she's defiant and she wants her parents to read it.
不 她注重隱私
No,but she's private.
她根本不會把這些想法寫下來
She wouldn't commit these thoughts to paper in the first place.
除非是被逼迫的
Unless it was forced on her.
你女兒的日記才寫了九個月
Your daughter's journal only goes back 9 months.
什麼促使她開始寫日記的?
What made her start keeping it?
我們去看了家庭顧問 他建議Jane開始寫日記
We went to a family counselor who suggested jane keep it.
- 他的辦公室在哪? - 在Tenderloin區
- Where was the office? - In the tenderloin district.
好 明白了 做的好 Morgan
Ok. Got it. Good work,morgan.
McBride一家去了Tenderloin區 一家心理治療中心
The mcbride family went to a therapy center in the tenderloin.
那地方同時給社會服務機構作評估
The place also did evaluations for social services.
根據側寫 不明疑犯可能失去了女兒監護權
We profiled that the unsub may have had his daughter taken away from him.
如果監護程序也是在那媔i行的 那麼他很清楚怎麼選擇目標父女
If he was processed in the same place, then he would know how to target the fathers and daughters.
- 我能跟你的分析師談談麼? - 當然
- Can i talk to your analyst? - Sure.
- 說吧 - Penelope Garcia 我是Sam Cooper
- Talk to me. - Penelope garcia. Sam cooper.
Sam Cooper?  在我有生之年 我一直認為你是個傳說
Sam cooper? As i live and breathe, and here i thought you were a story someone invented.
- 有什麼需要? - 這個要你幫忙查下
- What you got? - Here's what i need from you.
經社會機構服務 並最後失去女兒的人
Anyone processed by social services who ended up losing a daughter.
我不在乎這名單有多長
I don't care how big the list is.
我能交叉對照我已有的其他名單
I can cross-reference it against my others.
收到 雷厲風行
Roger that. Gonna hack like the wind.
等著被震驚吧 長官
Prepare to be wowed,sir.
Jane我要你聽我說
Jane.I need you to listen to me,
因為這可能是我最後一次和你談話
'cause it might be the last time i ever get to talk to you.
我是個不夠格的父親
I haven't been a good enough father.
你才14歲 你不知道這多可怕
You're 14. You have no idea how terrifying that is.
所以 我試著控制你行事  控制和你見面的人 因為我想讓你安全
So i've tried to control what you do and who you see, because i wanted to keep you safe.
我希望你能從學校畢業 找個好工作
And i wanted you to go off to school and get a good job
或許有一天 能墜入愛河
and maybe someday...Fall in love...
讓我能挽著你走過紅毯
And ask me to walk you down the aisle.
我仍然是你父親 守護你是我的責任
I'm still your dad, and it's my job to look out for you.
但我不曾是個好的傾聽者
But i haven't been a good listener.
我知道你聽得見我
I know you can hear me.
我沒想讓你有所回應
And i'm not asking you to say anything.
我只想讓你明白 我 我控制不了所有事情
I just want you to know that i understand that i--that i can't control everything.
但我希望你聽到我最後的話
But i need the last words you hear me say...
那就是 我愛你
To be that i love you.
好了 眾位盟友 我有份名單  都是經社會服務機構評估的父母
All right,my tribe, i have a list of parents, evaluated by social services,
最終都失去了監護權
Who ended up losing custody.
但正如Cooper所料  這是個漫長凄慘的故事
But as cooper predicted, it is a lengthy tale of woe.
我們要用這個名單 和在 可疑日期死亡的少女的名單比對
We'll use it to cross against the teenage girls who died on some of the dates in question.
我開始讀名字  你告訴我你那單子上有這名兒不
I'm going to start reading names. You tell me if they're on your list.
Maria Salter  Carla Denny... Joyce Collard  Dawn Sparrow...
恩 這個聽著有譜 謝啦 先知
Right. Sounds like a possible. Thanks,prophet.
有名字了 一個叫John Vincent Bell的
We have a name. A john vincent bell.
其中一個死亡的少女叫Mandy Bell
One of the girls who died was named mandy bell.
Garcia 在家庭心理治療名單中 查下John Vincent Bell
Garcia,run the name john vincent bell against the family therapy list.
有了 Bell和妻子離婚了 妻子之後死了
Shazzam. Bell and his wife divorced, then the wife died,
Bell被認為沒有能力撫養監護他女兒
And bell was declared incompetent to have custody of the daughter
- 因為一些精神問題 - 我們找到對的人了
- due to a host of mental health issues. - We got that one right.
啊 天啊 當社會服務機構出面 要帶走女孩的時候
Oh,lord. And then, when social service agents showed up to remove the girl,
Bell把其中一個毆打致死  因故意殺人判刑7年
Bell beat one of them to death, was given 7 years for manslaughter.
恩 在這段時間他女兒遭遇車禍
Yeah. During which time, his daughter was in a car accident.
靠生命維持系統堅持了三天 但最後還是因為腦損傷死亡
Looks like she survived 3 days on life support but eventually died of brain injuries.
好 所以Bell要這些人彼此拚死打鬥 就和他本人一樣
Ok,so bell is making these men fight to the death just like he did.
他在試圖證明 他做的和其他父親沒啥兩樣
He's trying to prove he did what any father would do.
有地址麼?
Do we have an address?
只有一個在Tenderloin區 霍爾大街的健身房地址
Uh,the only listing i have is a gym on hall street in the tenderloin.
是Bell的家產 已經幾年沒運作了
It belongs to bell's family. Hasn't been operational for years.
我們找到他了
We got him.
當Jane目睹你所做的一切的時候 我看了她的臉
I watched jane's face when she saw what you did.
我告訴過你 你毀不了我
I told you you won't break me.
沒關係 你已經失去她了
Doesn't matter. You already lost her.
但如果你想繼續反抗
But if you want to keep fighting...
- 他說的對 - Jane
- He's right. - Jane.
- 我希望你照顧我 - 什麼?
- I want you to take care of me. - What?
我爸爸騙了我 他本想把我送走的
My dad lied to me. He was gonna send me away.
- 好了 停下 - 他是個騙子
- All right,stop. - He's a liar.
- Janey 別說了 - 我恨你
- Janey,stop. - I hate you.
我可以跟你到任何地方去 但請讓我離開他
I will go anywhere you want. Just please get me away from him.
- 不 她不會的 - 求你了
- No,she won't. - Please.
聽我說 別這麼做  我會殺了你的 明白麼?
Listen to me. Stop this. I will kill you, you hear me?
我會找到你  我會殺了你 我會殺了你!
I will track you down and i will kill you. I will kill you!
- 我不這麼想 - 等等!
- I don't think so. - Wait!
你說 如果我跟你走 我們倆都有得活是麼?
You said if i go with you, we both live. Ok?
- 你不能騙我啊 - Janey
- I need to know you're not a liar,too. - Janey.
- 求你了 - 別這麼做 你在幹什麼 Jane?
- Please. - Don't do this. What are you doing,jane?
求你了...
Please...
Janey 別這樣 別 你到底要... Jane!
Janey,please don't do this. Don't--what do you--jane!
Janey! Janey! Jane!
JJ 上
Jj. Go.
安全
Clear.
Hotch
Hotch.
把槍放下!
Drop your gun!
霍爾大街631號 急需救護人員
I need paramedics immediately to 631 hall street.
- 先生 你女兒Jane呢? - 他把她帶走了
- Sir,where's your daughter jane? - He took her.
- 多長時間了? - 就幾分鐘 找到她
- How long ago? - Just a few minutes ago. Find her.
- 請找到她 - 我會的
- Please find her. - I will.
- 這堥S人 - 他在街上 帶著那個姑娘
- The place is clear. - He's on the street. He's got the girl.
- 我留下來守著父親 - Garcia 我需要John Vincent Bell的車輛信息
- I'll stay with the father. - Garcia,i need vehicle information for john vincent bell.
通知警方全境通緝
Tell police we need an apb.
Gina? 我是Cooper 該行動了
Gina? Cooper. You're on the move.
- 我可以從屋頂射擊 - 很好 去吧
- I can hit the rooftops. - Good. Go.
我需要直升機
I need a helicopter.
Garcia 通知舊金山警方 我們需要直升機
Garcia,tell san francisco p.d. We need a chopper.
大家保持通話 我幫你們看著
I need everybody on their radios. I'm gonna be your eyes.
來吧
All right,come on.
那兒 就在那兒
There. Right there.
發現目標 Turk和Franklin路口 東南角
We got a visual. Turk and franklin. Southeast corner.
離我們兩個路口遠
We're 2 blocks away.
- 站住! - 閉嘴!
- Stop! - Shut your mouth!
燈別照在街上
Don't shine it on the street.
- 那咱飛那麼高幹嘛? - 盯著屋頂就好
- Then why the hell are we up here? - Just give me the rooftop.
在那兒他無處可逃
He can't escape up there.
這人被單獨監禁了三年
This guy was locked alone in a box for 3 years.
如果被包圍了 就會做出本能反應
If he feels trapped, his animal instinct's gonna kick in.
上天入地也要逃命
He's either going to try to burrow or climb his way free.
如果不能挖洞 他肯定會走屋頂
And since he can't dig his way out of here, i guarantee you he's going to the roof.
大家注意 他要去屋頂 他要去屋頂
Everyone,be advised-- he's going to the roof. He's going to the roof.
救命! 救我! 你弄疼我了!
Help me! Help me! You're hurting me!
這邊
This way.
來!
Come on!
他要往東邊走 我們包圍他
He's headed to the east corner. We got him trapped.
John Bell  FBI! 放下武器!
John bell,fbi! Put the weapon down!
- 別開槍 - 放下槍!
- Don't shoot me. - Drop the gun!
照著他 別晃到我的探員
Keep it on him. Do not blind my agents.
你完了! 看看周圍!
It's over! Look around you!
別那樣! 放下!
Don't do it! Put it down!
你知道失去女兒的滋味
You know what if feels like to lose your daughter.
你真的想讓別人也受到這種傷害嗎?
Do you really want to hurt somebody else's?
從牆上下來!
Get off the wall!
McBride先生 你女兒在這兒 你太太正趕來
Mr. Mcbride,your daughter's here and your wife's on the way.
他們會送他去醫院
They're gonna take him to the hospital.
醫護人員說他不會有事的
The paramedics said he's going to be ok.
- 我能跟他說話嗎? - 當然可以
- Can i talk to him? - Yeah,of course.
- 寶貝兒 - 對不起
- Baby. - I'm so sorry.
- 我不是有意說那些話的 - 我知道
- I didn't mean any of the things that i said. - I know.
- 你差點死了 - 過來
- You could have died. - Just come here. Come here.
- 老爸我愛你 - 我也愛你 愛死了
- I love you,daddy. - I love you,too,so much.
我愛你
I love you.
媽
Mom.
謝謝
Thank you.
你們得小心這傢伙
You guys want to watch out for this one.
她且忘不了我了
She's gonna have a hard time getting over me.
像病毒一樣甩不掉
Like kicking a virus.
我本來有可能射偏的
You know, i could have just missed.
你這麼自大的? 不太可能
With your ego? Not a chance.
我覺得聖昆汀監獄比這兒好誒
I actually think san quentin was nicer.
- 相信我 根本不是那麼回事 - 你們在說啥?
- Yeah,trust me,it's not. - What do you mean?
我覺得你該留著這個
I think you should have this.
為什麼? 你側寫我?
Why? What,you're profiling me now?
她媽媽給我的
Her mom gave it to me.
這能讓你想起 相信直覺得到的好結果
I think it's time you have a reminder that trusting your gut has a happy ending.
你今天表現不錯
You did good today.
怎麼你直接打給我了?
Oh,so you're calling me directly now,huh?
別那麼無禮
Don't be insolent.
等你和Hotchner探員回來 還是要查清你們擅自行動的事情
I still plan on reading you and agent hotchner the riot act when you get back.
我萬分期待啊
Well... It's something to look forward to.
幹得漂亮 現在別傻了
You did good work. Now,don't be an idiot.
坐他們的飛機回來
Get on that jet with his team and get back home.
- 我有一堆案件要你處理 - 好的 長官
- I have a pile of cases for you. - Yes,ma'am.
她到底說什麼了?
So what exactly did she say?
- 她說等咱回去她請吃牛排大餐 - 是嘛
- She said that she's going to buy us a steak dinner when we get back. - Right.
謝謝你為我挺身而出
Thanks for putting yourself on the line for me.
隨時奉陪 謝謝你的直覺
Anytime. Thanks for being right.
乾杯!
Toast!
犯罪心理 第五季 第18集
== 結束 ==
Criminal Minds Season05 Episode18 The Fight